Jordan Ellis Bechek

Software Developer

I am, always have been, and always will be a problem solver and tinkerer, inquisitive in nature and imaginative at heart. I have been programming for nine years and am skilled in web development, database design, and mobile platform development.





bechek.jordan@gmail.com



Pittsburgh, PA



jbechek.github.io



in linkedin.com/in/jordan

Work Experience

Oracle Database Developer

Northrop Grumman 🗹

05/2019 - Present

Canonsburg, PA

- Maintain a large, complex database system used to facillitate and track the transfer of EDI transactions
- Design, develop, and deploy novel technical solutions to customer requests

Computer Systems Analyst

Northrop Grumman 🗹

09/2018 - 05/2019

Canonsburg, PA

- Developed various data-driven web applications, using ColdFusion to integrate backend databases
- Assisted with the finalization of the migration from Gentran to B2B

EDI Intern

Northrop Grumman 🗹

06/2018 - 09/2018

Canonsburg, PA

- Led the migration of business partners from FTP to SFTP using SSH2 key authentication, heightening security for EDI
- Developed data maps for inbound and outbound EDI using B2B Sterling Integrator

Application Support Intern

Aires 🗹

05/2017 - 08/2017

Robinson, PA

- Developed dynamic, client-facing forms using XML and
- Maintained various database schemas for customer data using PL/SQL
- Worked closely with not only the Application Support team, but also with QA, Development, and Busniess teams to ensure client satisfaction

Education

BA in Computing and Information Studies Washington & Jefferson College

09/2014 - 05/2018

- Graduated Magna Cum Laude
- Minors in Neuroscience and Philosophy

Projects

Real-Time Bus Tracking System ď

Completed for Project Management Course

Tracks Freedom Transit's busses in real-time using an Android tracker app, and displays bus and route info through a client-facing web application; uses Google Firebase and Google Maps API

Student's Edge Mobile Application

Based on project for App Design and Development Course

Hybrid app published on both the Google Play and Apple App Stores. Tracks students' classes, assignments, and grades; determines minimum required grades to reach student-set goal

Data Storage System

Completed for Advanced Database Concepts Course

Transactional database and data warehouse system for a DJ service; MySQL was used to design, develop, and maintain the system, along with automated data transference from short- to long-term storage

Eye Tracking Chess Players

Completed for Eye Tracking Methodology Course

Designed and carried out an experiment to determine what, if any, differences there are between eye movement patterns of novice and expert chess players

References

Charles Pfeffer, BS

EDI Manager Northrop Grumman 333 Technology Dr #250 Canonsburg, PA 15317, US

Email: cpfeffer@opentrac.com [2]

Charles T. Hannon, Ph.D.

Professor and Department Chair of CIS Washington & Jefferson College 50 S Lincoln St Washington, PA 15301, US Email: channon@washjeff.edu

Zach Hall, MIS

Manager of Application Support/Implementation Aires

6 Penn Center W #200 Pittsburgh, PA 15276, US Email: zhall@aires.com ☑

Languages & Software Skill Set



Awards & Accomplishments

David and Kristin Steinburg Scholarship in Computing and Information Studies 2016 Recipient

Phi Beta Kappa Honor Society 2018 Inductee

Phi Sigma Tau Honor Society 2018 Inductee